<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>San Antonio Developers</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://sanantoniodevs.com/</id><updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>How to join the Slack group</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/join-slack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2023-08-16:/join-slack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short tutorial on how to join the SA Devs Slack group&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How to join the Slack group&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Steps to join&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Slack group! We're glad you're here. To join the group, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the homepage, click "Slack" on the left sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept the Slack invite and create an account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the &lt;code&gt;#random&lt;/code&gt; channel and introduce yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review our &lt;a href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/pages/rules.html"&gt;community rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get oriented with the group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of channels in our Slack group. You can view all of our channels, or you can start joining channels of programming languages you like to use. We also have channels for specific topics, like &lt;code&gt;#random&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;#jobs&lt;/code&gt;. If you're a parent, we have a &lt;code&gt;#parentops&lt;/code&gt; channel for discussions on raising kids the DevOps way. Like sports? Join &lt;code&gt;#sports&lt;/code&gt;. Interested in travel? Check out &lt;code&gt;#travel&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of places where you can discuss your favorite topics and get to know other members in the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let any of the admins know if you have questions or concerns. We strive to be a welcoming and inclusive community, and we want to make sure you feel safe and comfortable here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to SA Devs!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="how-to"></category><category term="docs"></category></entry><entry><title>Season of Giving Finale</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/season-of-giving-2020-finale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Herrington</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2020-12-14:/season-of-giving-2020-finale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Results of Season of Giving 2020&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SA Devs Season of Giving Finale&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season of Giving is completed for 2020! Our community raised $1126.00 through our charitable donations and work in the month of November! The SA Devs organization has matched this with a $1126.00 donation to the SA Food Bank, providing meals for almost 8000 people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see all of our donations and totals on https://sanantoniodevs.com/season-of-giving-2020.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am personally overwhelmed with gratitude and pride for everyone who participated. Thank you all for helping to end food insecurity here in South Texas!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="season-of-giving"></category><category term="donations"></category><category term="charity"></category></entry><entry><title>Advent of Code (AoC) 2020 Code Jam</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/advent-of-code-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jason Gutierrez</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2020-11-29:/advent-of-code-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open invitation to the SA Developers Advent of Code leaderboard and code jam&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Third Annual SA Developers Advent of Code (AoC) Code Jam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome all members of the San Antonio Web Developers community and Slack group. I do
apologize for the late entry for this article but better late then never. At the time of
this writing there are 1 day(s) until the first challenge is released on Dec 1, 2020 Midnight EST.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an open invitation and challenge to all developers who want to flex their skills
or try out a new language while solving programming puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Advent of Code (AoC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with AoC, I would recommend that you go to their about page &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2020/about"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt;
A new puzzle is released / unlocked at midnight EST/UTC-5 every day from Dec 1 to Dec 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Join&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you will need to sign in to &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;, You can link
with your Github, Google or Email address. Once you are registered you can join the SA Developers
private leaderboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the private leaderboard, click on the link &lt;code&gt;[LeaderBoard]&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;[Private Leaderboard]&lt;/code&gt;
There should be an input box for you to enter the private leaderboard code below to join in on the
reindeer games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or just use this link &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2020/leaderboard/private"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and enter the code below.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SA DEVS PRIVATE LEADERBOARD CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;215653-c4570711&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also post comments / questions / ~~boast of programming superiority~~ help other
members of the SADev community. This should be a &lt;strong&gt;FUN&lt;/strong&gt; way to interact with each other. &lt;strong&gt;#devsbeingchill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this worth my time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectively, YES. You get to meet / compete with other developers in the SA Developer community
and bask in the glory that is being higher ranked than some other seasoned developers. Bwahahaha!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a gift card / cash prize for the winner or potential winners at the end of the challenge.
As of this writing, the current prize is valued at 💰$10💰. The prize purse can potentially grow depending
on the generousity of other developers in the community who wish to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRIZE CONTRIBUTORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;@cptcrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="code-jam"></category><category term="aoc"></category></entry><entry><title>SA Devs Season of Giving</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/season-of-giving-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Herrington</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2020-11-01:/season-of-giving-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let's come together as a community to do some good this season!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SA Devs Season of Giving&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Season of Giving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the month of November, let's work together as a group to give to those who can use some help. Donate to your 
favorite charity (we've got some suggestions below), submit your receipt to SA Devs, and we'll amplify your donation. At
the end of the month, the SA Devs org will match up to $2000 of community donations to the SA Food Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to sponsor some matching funds? You can sponsor a day, a week, or the entire month and any amount/total. Reach out
to the admins and we'll add your matching and notify you of totals!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also understand some people might want to donate in other ways and we want to celebrate that too! If you donate your 
time, canned goods, or do any other charitable work and you'd like it celebrated as part of SA Devs Season of Giving,
reach out to the admins and we'll add it to our donation list! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Suggested Charities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are charities that we feel are doing good work in our community. Don't feel like you have to donate to these 
organizations, but if you're looking for a place to donate these are good choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have an organization you like to work with? Reach out to the admins and we'll add it to our list!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;San Antonio Food Bank&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://safoodbank.org/"&gt;https://safoodbank.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hill Country Daily Bread&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hillcountrydailybread.com/"&gt;https://hillcountrydailybread.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Get Up Community Center&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.getupcommunity.org/food-pantry"&gt;https://www.getupcommunity.org/food-pantry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to record a donation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a screenshot or PDF of your donation receipt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a DM to &lt;code&gt;@sadevbot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send &lt;code&gt;./donation {amount} --make-public&lt;/code&gt; and attach your receipt to the message 
If you want to keep your donation private (the admins will still see your name/info but we won't put it on the site) 
leave out --make-public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your amount matches the amount on your receipt. You can enter it as $##.## i.e. $20.00 (or even just $20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadevbot will send your donation on to the admins for review and it'll get added to the website (just below here in 
the donations list). Private donations will just list an amount. The bot will also update totals in 
&lt;code&gt;#sadevs-season-of-giving-2020&lt;/code&gt; regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to do if you have an issue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bot didn't work? Donation didn't show up? Messed up entering a donation? Something else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DM any of the admins and we can help. We can record your donation manually, delete a donation for you to resubmit, or 
kick the bot into working again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donation Total And List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Donation Total: $1126.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jacob Herrera - $100.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Hebert - $10.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Herrington - $17.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omar Quimbaya - $300.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private - $415.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry Gonzales - $100.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private - $67.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private - $100.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Herrington - $17.00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="season-of-giving"></category><category term="donations"></category><category term="charity"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacktoberfest or Spamtoberfest?</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/hacktoberfest-or-spamtoberfest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jason Gutierrez</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2020-10-05:/hacktoberfest-or-spamtoberfest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An opinion on contributing to open source projects during Hacktoberfest&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;To Hacktober or Not to Hacktober?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in light of some recent events, mostly from a Youtuber with a large following,
there was a "wave" of "spammy" PRs (Pull Requests) where "contributors" would
add some text without much context and would be considered valid PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sympathize with the Youtuber, and I believe they had good intentions, but I believe
this lines up with the overall mentality of Imposter Syndrome which many of us, including
myself, share. The concept of contributing to an open source project is noble and exciting.
Some projects are only alive because of a community that enjoys the service or project
that has postively impacted their profession. (&lt;a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust"&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;). However, I think there is an underlying barrier
that can scare off would be contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These contributors instead only "contribute" by correcting &lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt;s. Generally,
PRs should address issues raised by others contributing to the project. Corrections
to a projects' &lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt; is warranted but should impactful to the reader rather than
a 👍 reaction / comment for the sake of only making a PR. Maybe the results of the "spam"
PRs is due to some unintentional intimidation that even some more seasoned developers have experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of these outcomes and sentiments I believe that the open source community
shouldn't suffer because of this but rather "inform" would be contributors and follow
a sort of "honor" system. It should be considered a "given" or even an expectation that
open source projects would be subject to being "spammed". Perhaps if these projects were more
prepared and prefaced with a more "beginner" friendly set of instructions, they could
reduce the "contributor" learning curve. Maybe, create a &lt;code&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/code&gt; to a project
to help other open source contributors. 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recommendations to contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to contribute to an open source project, be mindful of your contribution.
You may only interact with this project once in your life, more specifically only during Hacktoberfest.
Imagine you are a "tourist" in France and you would like to add your "Lock of Love" to a
particular chain-link fence. Your contribution may not seem like much, but as a city employee
that might have to "maintain" said fence, it can be overwhelming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city employee(s) that maintains the fence of locks is aware of these contributions 
and should provide guidelines to would be "romeos" about the Do's and Don't of adding a lock to the fence.
Order and community rules allow for a more enjoyable experience for all who chose to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a contributor, don't be afraid of rules or for that matter, contributing. It is an experience that
many don't get the chance to take part of. It is an act that allows us to become an active member
of our tech community and even grow as a developer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe your &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; PR is editing a README, that's okay. Challenge yourself to make more "meaningful"
contributions to the open source community and projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="opinion"></category><category term="article"></category></entry><entry><title>Goodbye 2019! Hello, 2020!</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/goodbye-2019-hello-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-12-23:/goodbye-2019-hello-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A reflection of our community in 2019&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andrew Herrington, Daniel Wallce, Doug Mendizabal, and I started this group on July 24, 2017. The idea to create a slack community of developers from around San Antonio came from a developer named Mark. He had recently come in from Tennessee and reached out to Omar via the Geekdom Slack. He was looking for a place where developers could share ideas and be language agnostic, and in Nashville, they had a slack community with developers from all over the city. Why didn't San Antonio have that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we had the Geekdom slack, but not everyone who was a developer has a $50 a month membership to that coworking space, so the cost alone was prohibitive, and the slack group itself was declining in terms of its community participation. There had to be something better, so the four banded together and worked on building a developer community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since then, our community has grown from those 5 developers (Mark included) to 474 members. Of those 474 members, 71 are currently active, as of writing this blog post. We have not been tracking a lot of metrics from our slack group since its inception, but over the course of two years, we think this is pretty good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the goals of the community? Developers to connect, help each other out, and grow as professionals in their craft. The way we support this is by making sure the slack community is an inclusive one where people of all walks of life are welcome; however, there are opportunities for us to improve on this. We welcome community feedback, as well, to help us improve as admins. Please feel free to reach out to us in the DMs if you have feedback or questions. We also support the goals by having quaterly meetups featuring talks from non-technical topics to technical topics. This helps people be introduced to new ideas, develop their soft-skills, meet new people by putting a face to a screenname, and feed them for an evening. These meetups would not have happened without the help of Jon Robers in our group. He took up the sword of event development, organized the admin team, and created some great meetups throughout the year. We are very grateful for the time and work he had put into making those meetups successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our community also started two open source projects: Barbacoa and PuroEvents. People within our community have the opportunity to dive in and contribute to those projects as they see fit, and that helps new developers get into open source software development, as well. It's a great way for experienced developers to mentor new people, too, so the opportunity is there for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, for the outgoing year, we say thank you to everyone who contributed content, advice, articles, meetups, talks, fellowship, questions, answers, and more to our group. For the incoming year, we are looking forward to our quarterly meetups, growing our community, brining additional perspectives and viewpoints to our group, and saying goodbye to Python 2.7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to help out the SA Devs group in any way, please let us know by messaging any of the admins (Andrew, Daniel, Doug, and me). We are all dedicated to making sure this community runs like a well-documented framework in the hands of a mid-level developer aiming to 10x their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to see what 2020 will bring our community, and we are excited to be here with you all having a good time and growing as a collective group of developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy new year, SA Devs! &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="updates"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>San Antonio Devs Meetup - Q4 2019</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/q4-2019-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-12-12:/q4-2019-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Information about the San Antonio Devs Q4 2019 meetup&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are pumped up for our Q4 meetup! Please click the link below to RSVP and reserve your spot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sa-devs-q4-2019-meetup-tickets-81751168947"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sa-devs-q4-2019-meetup-tickets-81751168947&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Academy will be sponsoring this meetup by providing pizza! Thank you, Linux Academy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on Linux Academy and their courses on many things open source and cloud, go to &lt;a href="https://linuxacademy.com/"&gt;https://linuxacademy.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome and networking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News you can use from the SA Devs group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Bailey - CLI Tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a Python developer you have probably used many command line tools and maybe even had to write a few yourself. Writing CLI tools can be anywhere from really fun to really frustrating. This talk will go over three popular CLI libraries argparse, click, and fire. These libraries can help you write a command line applications in Python. However, every project has different goals and requirements, so there isn't one clear winner. This guide will help you choose one that fits your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, this talk is structured in a choose your own adventure style and the audience will get to vote on the direction of the talk via a realtime voting system online. So have a phone or laptop ready to vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Perez - Who called it agile and not fast feedback?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is over our tendency to over-codify the agile process into something that is not at all agile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These talks should be fantastic, so please be sure to show up for our last meetup of the year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>Advent of Code (AoC) 2019 Code Jam</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/advent-of-code-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jason Gutierrez</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-11-25:/advent-of-code-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open invitation to the SA Developers Advent of Code leaderboard and code jam&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Second Annual SA Developers Advent of Code (AoC) Code Jam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome all members of the San Antonio Web Developers community and Slack group. I do
apologize for the late entry for this article but better late then never. At the time of
this writing there are 5 days until the first challenge is released on Dec 1, 2019 Midnight EST.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an open invitation and challenge to all developers who want to flex their skills
or try out a new language while solving programming puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Advent of Code (AoC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with AoC, I would recommend that you go to their about page &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2019/about"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt;
A new puzzle is released / unlocked at midnight EST/UTC-5 every day from Dec 1 to Dec 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Join&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you will need to sign in to &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;, You can link
with your Github, Google or Email address. Once you are registered you can join the SA Developers
private leaderboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the private leaderboard, click on the link &lt;code&gt;[LeaderBoard]&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;[Private Leaderboard]&lt;/code&gt;
There should be an input box for you to enter the private leaderboard code below to join in on the
reindeer games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or just use this link &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2019/leaderboard/private"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and enter the code below.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SA DEVS PRIVATE LEADERBOARD CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;215653-c4570711&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also post comments / questions / ~~boast of programming superiority~~ help other
members of the SADev community. This should be a &lt;strong&gt;FUN&lt;/strong&gt; way to interact with each other. &lt;strong&gt;#devsbeingchill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this worth my time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectively, YES. You get to meet / compete with other developers in the SA Developer community
and bask in the glory that is being higher ranked than some other seasoned developers. Bwahahaha!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a gift card / cash prize for the winner or potential winners at the end of the challenge.
As of this writing, the current prize is valued at 💰$10💰. The prize purse can potentially grow depending
on the generousity of other developers in the community who wish to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRIZE CONTRIBUTORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;@cptcrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="code-jam"></category><category term="aoc"></category></entry><entry><title>San Antonio Devs Meetup - 2019 Q3</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/q3-2019-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jon Roberts</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-09-17:/q3-2019-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Series of Lightning Talks from Community Members at the Geekdom Event Center!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our first ever series of community lightning talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit your talk here: https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSedSyp98xFyQ6P_Iluy3RQD8v4400Ua8-_HES_uLKAqUoS28g/viewform?usp=sf_link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP at the link Below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/san-antonio-devs-meetup-2019-q3-tickets-70171588109"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/san-antonio-devs-meetup-2019-q3-tickets-70171588109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and drinks will be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7pm        Welcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:10       Community Lightning Talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:40-7:50  Intermission and reload your snacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:50       More Community Lightning talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:20       Food &amp;amp; Fellowship&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>San Antonio Devs Meetup - Q2 2019</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/q2-2019-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jon Roberts</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-04-29:/q2-2019-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Information about the San Antonio Devs Q2 2019 meetup&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're excited to see you at our Q2 Meetup!  Please RSVP at the link Below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/san-antonio-software-developers-2019-q2-meetup-tickets-61037466706"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/san-antonio-software-developers-2019-q2-meetup-tickets-61037466706&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light refreshments will be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7pm        Welcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:15       "Cloud-Native" Software Design and Architecture - Jon Roberts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:40       Break and Open Space event planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:10       Mentoring 101 - Ell Marquez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:35       Raffle Drawing, Food &amp;amp; Fellowship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9:00       Launch SA might be telling us to leave ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>A Chinese New Year Dinner for Devs</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/sichuan-house-new-year-dinner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-02-23:/sichuan-house-new-year-dinner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Chinese New Year Dinner for the SA Developers!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy year of the pig, SA Devs! &lt;img alt="Pig" src="/images/zodiac-pig.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be having our first scheduled dinner together at one of the best Chinese restaurants in San Antonio: Sichuan House. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sichuan food is known to be spicy (peppercorns) and flavorful, so make sure to gather your dependencies and prepare for some spicy food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eating style will be communal, so you won't have your own order -- we're all sharing the bill! We will order some plates of meat and vegetables and share from those plates. We will also get some white rice and cold dishes to whet our appetites and fill our bellies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's celebrate the Year of the Pig as the lazy developers we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note about the year of the pig:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pig is not thought to be a smart animal in China. It likes sleeping and eating and becomes fat. Thus it usually features laziness and clumsiness. On the positive side, it behaves itself, has no plan to harm others, and can bring affluence to people. Consequently, it has been regarded as wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="https://www.travelchinaguide.com/intro/social_customs/zodiac/pig.htm"&gt;https://www.travelchinaguide.com/intro/social_customs/zodiac/pig.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>San Antonio Devs Meetup - Q1 2019</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/q1-2019-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Wallace</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-02-12:/q1-2019-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Information about the first San Antonio Devs meetup of 2019!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first meetup of the San Antonio Devs group is coming up!  Please RSVP at the link Below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sanantonio-devs-meetup-q1-2019-tickets-56443738742"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sanantonio-devs-meetup-q1-2019-tickets-56443738742&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food will be available, but it will be for purchase and cash only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7pm        Welcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:15       Daniel Wallace - Rapid Prototyping a New API in Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:40-7:45  Break and speaker switch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:50       Robert Castillo - Leadership Skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:20       Raffle drawing, Food &amp;amp; fellowship&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>Meeting for Noodles - January 2019</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/januarynoodles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jon Roberts</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2019-01-18:/januarynoodles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Social Gathering for Noodles and Stuff&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several members are meeting to share some Noodles. I will be partaking in Sushi, though, as that is a gluten-free option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited about this one, as I love Sushi and I like trying new places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the members planning to attend are remote developers. If you work remotely, be sure to get out of the house and meet some of your fellow hermits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kimura is downtown and Friday is the first day of PAX South 2019, which I know some of our members are attending.  I hope they also bring some interesting out of towners that they meet at the convention!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>Meeting for Noodles</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/decembernoodles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jon Roberts</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2018-12-05:/decembernoodles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Social Gathering for Pho and Stuff&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several members are meeting to share some Pho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited about this one, as I love Pho and I like trying new places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the members planning to attend are remote developers. If you work remotely, be sure to get out of the house and meet some of your fellow hermits.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry><entry><title>Podcasts on Development</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/podcasts-on-development.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2018-12-01:/podcasts-on-development.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short survey of interesting podcasts to listen to about development.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Podcasts on Development&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love listening to podcasts. It is like listening to your own personal radio station where they talk about things you care about and want to learn about. Podcasts have been exploding in recent years because they are accessible, interesting, and allow anyone the opportunity to share a story, illustrate their expertise, or report on a niche topic that is under-represented by the general news media. Software development, Devops, programming, and tech in general have a lot of niche topics within, and there are plenty of podcasts out there covering many aspects of the field in which we all work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, because podcasts are so prevalent and easy to produce, the quality of them vary, so it is hard to know what is good and what is not good without spending a lot of time listening to these shows and getting a feel for them. A quick look at &lt;a href="https://simpleprogrammer.com/ultimate-list-developer-podcasts/"&gt;https://simpleprogrammer.com/ultimate-list-developer-podcasts/&lt;/a&gt; shows us the sheer amount of podcasts that are out there for different topics within development, so it can be a dizzying experience trying to pick one that is potentially of a high enough quality to deserve our subscription and time to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will make a few recommendations based on the podcasts that I listen to and provide some guidance on how best to approach finding your next favorite software development podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bikeshed.fm/"&gt;The Bike Shed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bike Shed is a podcast from the good people at &lt;a href="https://thoughtbot.com/"&gt;ThoughtBot&lt;/a&gt;. ThoughtBot is a software development firm that creates apps for both small and large customers. A San Antonio equivalent would be &lt;a href="https://grok.rocks"&gt;Grok Interactive&lt;/a&gt;, which actually used to have a podcast but stopped due to timing constraints. The Bike Shed focuses on the experiences and thoughts of the developers at ThoughtBot as they talk about some of the things they are working on, both professionally and contributing to open source, and what they think about what they are doing. A notable episode that I would recommend people to listen to first before diving into the Bike Shed would be episode 172: &lt;a href="http://bikeshed.fm/172"&gt;What I Believe About Software&lt;/a&gt;. In that episode, they talk about the core processes they use to develop software, focusing on planning, deadlines, code reviews, and retrospectives. Quite often, we think about software as something that is written once and it is all done, but much like any quality writing, software needs to be rewritten, reconfigured, retooled, etc at a regular enough cadence to keep it efficient, clean, and maintainable. For an understanding of why the show is called "The Bike Shed," see this article &lt;a href="http://bikeshed.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Fun note: every time you load the site, the background is a different color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://talkpython.fm/"&gt;Talk Python To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am biased here as my language of choice is Python, but one of the things that makes this podcast great are the guests that come in and talk about what they are doing to move Python forward, whether that's contributing directly to Python or creating libraries and frameworks to keep developers productive. A noteable episode to check out is the episode where they talk about what is new in Flask 1.0, which can be found here: &lt;a href="https://talkpython.fm/episodes/show/177/flask-goes-1.0"&gt;https://talkpython.fm/episodes/show/177/flask-goes-1.0&lt;/a&gt;. Flask is a micro web framework written in Python, and it is often used to build web services, APIs, or quick proof of concepts. It's an amazing little framework that is very flexible and allows developers to pick and choose how they want to use the tool instead of the tool dictating how it should be used. Flask had been at version 0.12 for a long time, so when it finally hit 1.0, this was a big deal for the Python community, especially those who use Python for the web. In the interview, the maintainer talks about the story behind Flask and where Flask is going next. One of my favorite things about this episode is when they talk about how easy it can be to contribute to open source projects. I believe conversations like that are important to encourage those out there that want to contribute something but are unsure of how best to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.smashingsecurity.com/"&gt;Smashing Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, hear me out here -- I know I am talking about development and programming, but I am sharing a security podcast that is not boring and makes security a more fun topic to discuss. Smashing Security is hosted by Graham Cluley and Carole Theriault, two security veterans, and they are full of personality, have great perspectives on security, and share some of the top news of the week without bogging you down with a ton of stories. They each bring a story to report and go into deep details about that story, helping you get context around the story and understand the security implication. Did I mention that they are also pretty hilarious? I enjoy their banter back and forward, and they keep me engaged throughout the show. One of the best parts of the show is the Pick of the Week, which is a segment where they share something that is not necessarily security-related. I get to learn about cool websites and tools from them during this segment, and I usually share those findings with people in our Slack channel or with my coworkers. As developers, having an understanding of security and being aware of what is going on in our worl of technology helps us make better decisions when writing software. No customer ever asked for the buffer overflow in their product. A noteable episode has to be the one where Graham learns about what Rule 34 is (&lt;a href="https://www.smashingsecurity.com/101"&gt;https://www.smashingsecurity.com/101&lt;/a&gt;). It is just too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are three recommendations for podcasts to check out that I can vouch for as I have been listening to them for a long time, but if you are looking for something new to listen to, please check out this resource &lt;a href="https://simpleprogrammer.com/ultimate-list-developer-podcasts/"&gt;https://simpleprogrammer.com/ultimate-list-developer-podcasts/&lt;/a&gt; for more shows that might help you grow in your career. A simple piece of advice, though: when going  through that giant list, focus on the things that you care about. What are you learning now, and what podcasts exist for that particular topic? You will not become a software development master by listening to podcasts, but what listening to podcasts does for you is expose you to new concepts and ideas to explore later. Part of learning is also exploring the known unknowns and discovering things that used to be unknown unknowns. Podcasts provide us this opportunity, and I recommend everyone check out something new when they get a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your favorite development or tech podcasts? Share them in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="opinion"></category><category term="podcasts"></category><category term="resources"></category></entry><entry><title>Advent of Code (AoC) 2018 Code Jam</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/advent-of-code-coding-jam.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jason Gutierrez</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2018-11-30:/advent-of-code-coding-jam.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open invitation to the SA Developers Advent of Code leaderboard and code jam&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;First Annual SA Developers Advent of Code (AoC) Code Jam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome all members of the San Antonio Web Developers community and Slack group. I do
apologize for the late entry for this article but better late then never. At the time of
this writing there are 13 hrs (CST) until the first challenge is released.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an open invitation and challenge to all developers who want to flex their skills
or try out a new language while solving programming puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Advent of Code (AoC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with AoC, I would recommned that you go to their about page &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2018/about"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and skill levels that can be solved in any programming language you like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new puzzle is release / unlocked at midnight EST/UTC-5 every day from Dec 1 to Dec 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Do I Join&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you will need to sign in to &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;, You can link
with your Github, Google or Email address. Once you are registered you can join the SA Developers
private leaderboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the private leaderboard, click on the link &lt;code&gt;[LeaderBoard]&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;[Private Leaderboard]&lt;/code&gt;
There should be an input box for you to enter the private leaderboard code below to join in on the
reindeer games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or just use this link &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/2018/leaderboard/private"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and enter the code below.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SA DEVS PRIVATE LEADERBOARD CODE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;215653-c4570711&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also post comments / questions / ~~boast of programming superiority~~ help other
members of the SADev community. This should be a &lt;strong&gt;FUN&lt;/strong&gt; way to interact with each other. &lt;strong&gt;#devsbeingchill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is this worth my time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectively, YES. You get to meet / compete with other developers in the SA Developer community
and bask in the glory that is being higher ranked than some other seasoned developers. Bwahahaha!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a gift card / cash prize for the winner or potential winners at the end of the challenge.
As of this writing, the current prize is valued at 💰$70💰. The prize purse can potentially grow depending
on the generousity of other developers in the community who wish to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRIZE CONTRIBUTORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;@bigjonroberts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;@cptcrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;@gtmanfred&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="code-jam"></category><category term="aoc"></category></entry><entry><title>How to add docs to this site</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/how-to-add-docs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2018-11-29:/how-to-add-docs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short tutorial of how to add your docs to this site and share your knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First of all, why would you want to do this? We are a group of developers who are active in our Slack group, but one of the main problems is that we have a lot of knowledge that we are not writing down in a more permanent place. When we share articles or advice on a technical topic, those messages will get lost with all of the other messages that people are sending as we are not paying for our Slack subscription. Therefore, in order to share our knowledge with people and show other cities that the developers in San Antonio are knowledgeable, collaborative, and willing to share their experience with the rest of the world, we are giving developers here an opportunity to share articles on their thoughts, experiences, and knowledge of how to use the technologies we use every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good opportunity for you to contribute something to the community without that much effort! In order to do so, here is how you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fork the repo!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our site is a static site hosted somewhere out there on the Internet. Super mysterious. You can find the repository of our site here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/SADevs/sadevs.github.io"&gt;https://github.com/SADevs/sadevs.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/en/articles/fork-a-repo"&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the website's repo and &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-Basics-Getting-a-Git-Repository"&gt;clone&lt;/a&gt; it to your local machine. Below are quick steps to clone your fork, update all the submodules (important to get our theme pulled down), and add the main repo as an upstream (important for syncing your fork later): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;git&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;clone&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;your&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;fork&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
git&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;submodule&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;update&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--init
git&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;remote&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;add&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;upstream&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;git@github.com:SADevs/sadevs.github.io.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Syncing your fork&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've already forked the repo and want to sync it, &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/en/articles/syncing-a-fork"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; offers some great documentation on doing it. If you cloned the repo following the above steps, you can follow the Github's documentation. If you didn't check out &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/en/articles/configuring-a-remote-for-a-fork"&gt;these directions&lt;/a&gt; for adding the remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to sync your fork after any changes are made in the main repo (like your PR being merged).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pelican Power!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is powered by &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, which is a static site generator written in Python. If you have Python on your machine and you want to see what your article looks like on your local machine, install Pelican by typing in your terminal &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# if you don&amp;#39;t have pipenv on your machine already&lt;/span&gt;
pip&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipenv
pipenv&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about &lt;a href="https://realpython.com/pipenv-guide/"&gt;pipenv here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will get the necessary packages to use this static site generator. To build and run the site locally, use the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;pipenv&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;run&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pelican&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;content&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-vvv&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-o&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;output&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-s&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pelicanconf.py
pipenv&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;run&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pelican&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--listen
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a browser and go to http://localhost:8000 to view the content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note that the links will link to the actual site instead of the locally generated site, so if you made changes and you are not seeing them, check the URL at the top to see where you are.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Article Template&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy this template to get you started into a new file with a relevant name of your article and ending with a markdown extension:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Title: How to install Pelican
Date: 11-29-2018
Tags: how-to, docs
Slug: how-to-install-pelican
Authors: Omar Quimbaya
Summary: A short tutorial on how to install Pelican

&lt;span class="gh"&gt;# How to install Pelican&lt;/span&gt;

&amp;lt;some text goes here&amp;gt;

    # code example
    print(&amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot;)

&lt;span class="gu"&gt;## Secondary Heading&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="gu"&gt;### Tertiary Heading&lt;/span&gt;

[&lt;span class="nt"&gt;Links for more information&lt;/span&gt;](&lt;span class="na"&gt;https://blog.getpelican.com/&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Making a PR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your document is done and you feel like you've said all you could about a topic, commit and push that to the &lt;code&gt;website&lt;/code&gt; branch of your clone repository. Go to your repo and submit a pull request to add your changes to the site. Once an admin reviews your article and accepts the pull request, it will start a process that will publish the article to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reviewing a PR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you've made your PR, if you want to spin up a review copy of the website, post in #website and one of the admins can spin up a copy of your changes for review. This will be a separate copy of the site running in Heroku so you can test all of your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions or run into any issues, reach out in #website on Slack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy writing, and thank you for contributing to the SA Developers Group!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="how-to"></category><category term="docs"></category></entry><entry><title>The Third SA Devs Meetup</title><link href="https://sanantoniodevs.com/thirdmeetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Omar Quimbaya</name></author><id>tag:sanantoniodevs.com,2018-10-25:/thirdmeetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A brief summary of our third meetup at iHeartMedia&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentations&lt;/strong&gt;: Shane on WebSockets, Big Jon on Knowing Thyself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a good group of people go up to iHeartMedia, eat pizza, hang out, and listen to some great presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides from the WebSockets discussion and the Github repo with the code: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/15ihtz4B9f0ArCAsqdCZn2wBWPlS3ogmvoMlL442n0us"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="https://github.com/th3n3wguy/sadevs-websocket-demo"&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;. The slides from Big Jon's talk are coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, iHeartMedia is doing a ton of hiring, so if you are interested in what positions are available at iHeart, &lt;a href="http://iheartmediacareers.com/Pages/default.aspx"&gt;check out this site.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the planning stages of the next meetup, but in the meantime go check out the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Alamo-City-Python-Group/events/255866995/"&gt;Python group&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday of next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="events"></category></entry></feed>